[
    {
        "question": "1. Romeo and Juliet is a tragedy because", 
        "optionA": "it is full of noblemen and ladies", 
        "optionB": "it is set in Verona", 
        "optionC": "it ends unhappily",
        "optionD": "it has five acts",
        "answer": "it ends unhappily"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. A literary work in which the characters and events are used as symbols is known as _________?", 
        "optionA": "characteristics", 
        "optionB": "allegory", 
        "optionC": "metaphor",
        "optionD": "parallelism",
        "answer": "allegory" 
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Drama is the representation of a complete series of actions by means of _________",
        "optionA": "movement and gesture for the screen and audience",
        "optionB": "speech, movement and gesture for the stage only",
        "optionC": "speech, movement and gesture for the stage, screen and radio",
        "optionD": "speech, gesture and movement for the screen and radio",
        "answer": "speech, movement and gesture for the stage, screen and radio"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. Which of these is the meaning of “CAST”?",
        "optionA": "a list of all characters in a drama", 
        "optionB": "what the character is saying",
        "optionC": "the person who writes the drama",
        "optionD": "a list of protagonists in a drama",
        "answer": "a list of all characters in a drama"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. This element shows how sections are separated into parts with numbers and titles_____________",
        "optionA": "Paragraph",
        "optionB": "Theme",
        "optionC": "Chapters",
        "optionD": "Characters",
        "answer": "Chapters"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. A folk-tale is a__________?",
        "optionA": "Novel",
        "optionB": "Biography",
        "optionC": "Work Of Fiction",
        "optionD": "Novelette",
        "answer": "Work Of Fiction"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Tell me not, sweet, I am unkind' illustrates_________",
        "optionA": "inversion",
        "optionB": "paradox",
        "optionC": "humor",
        "optionD": "mood",
        "answer": "paradox"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Define 'rhyme'?",
        "optionA": "comparing two things sounds",
        "optionB": "the repetition of a letter",
        "optionC": "the repetition of an ending sound",
        "optionD": "the repetition of vowel sounds",
        "answer": "the repetition of an ending sound"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. A Sonnet has a final couplet when it has___________",
        "optionA": "A sestet",
        "optionB": "An octave",
        "optionC": "Two sestets",
        "optionD": "Three quatrains",
        "answer": "Three quatrains"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. A short play perfomed during the pause between the acts of a longer play is____________",
        "optionA": "An Interlude",
        "optionB": "An epilogue",
        "optionC": "A prologue",
        "optionD": "An interval",
        "answer": "An Interlude"
    }
]